so welcome to the Mastermind on chronic
diseases
and what that is what does it mean how
can we deal what really is a chronic
disease and what does our body do when
it decides to go chronic
um so this is The Mastermind of
April 2nd in 2023 and we are getting
started so let me introduce the topic a
little bit and myself and I'm going to
start with this statement
we all have chronic issues why am I
saying that because
nature never is perfect we're all born
with
defects or weaknesses or
um challenges or physical
defects most of the time
um the the difficulties that we have are
reflected in our biology
and vice versa when they are biological
defects right in quotation marks then
that can reflect on our mental or
emotional stability so what is the word
chronic of course we all understand that
it's something that lasts a long time it
comes from the Greek word Kronos and
um has been
going into the Latin language and then
into the all the other European
languages so we have adopted this word
chronic disease and when you look it up
today in our wonderful interwebs it
stands for kind of mostly irreversible
illnesses
and
we can easily
find what belongs to these irreversible
illnesses
it seems to be a difficult internet day
because people are dropping in and out
Leah is that an internet issue you're
having
I saw that Arnie dropped out twice to
there you are
okay so having a chronic
disease
um okay I'm going into has of course
being very beneficial for certain
industries right
I have long said we don't have a health
insurance or a health industry because
it doesn't ensure that we're healthy
what does it ensure and how does it make
money right we have a disease industry
and a disease insurance
so
therefore we get all our systems
um mixed up or our our understanding of
the biological systems mixed up by
thinking that
a disease is something that falls upon
us
just by bad luck
and Circumstance and then we're
Afflicted with this
disease and this particular chronic
disease
so
um
I wanted to ask my audience you know who
here thinks that they have a chronic
disease now of course I've defined it
already so I should have asked
beforehand who he thinks you have a
chronic disease if you can put it in the
chat
and that would be great or if you could
just wave and say me
um
I would know that you realize that there
is something that you would call a
chronic disease now of course we have
very much
more tragic chronic diseases in
especially this United States of America
and those are
from heart disease to diabetes and
allergies and arthritis and Asthma Etc
all of these other issues in between
and we consider them chronic because we
say they cannot be reversed or they
cannot be cured they can only be managed
and of course that is the best way of
retaining chronic customers isn't it
so
I want to of course dispute that today
that it doesn't have to be
a chronic disease because biology always
rejuvenates itself if only we give it a
chance
now we can enumerate these particular
so-called chronic diseases by saying you
know this heart disease this diabetes
stroke is considered a chronic disease
interestingly so I have another chronic
disease I was going to tell you about
some of mine
um just because I had one stroke
never anything again but because
I did something
different
cancer is a chronic disease now in
today's definition obesity and I Leah
you need to listen to this obesity is
considered a chronic disease
mostly irreversible so you need your
daughter and your son-in-law to listen
to this
if obesity is considered a chronic
disease
no regular medical system will have the
courage to
even attempt to reverse it other than
surgically removing fat or or you know
body mass
um and or a similar operations so then
there's arthritis and there are
allergies
um which is another interesting
phenomenon right never in this
history have there been so many
allergies mind you I'm not saying they
haven't been reactions to toxins in the
world yes they have we just didn't call
them allergies for example before the
chemical treatments of Agriculture there
has been the use of arsenic as a
pesticide
and of course when the fields were
um strewn with this powder powdered
arsenic then um
that could cause severe reactions in the
people administering that or eating
those crops or being exposed to those
um things those chemicals
so as of the Industrial Age we have a
whole lot of more exposures to all kinds
of
chemistry that is toxic to the human
body and kind of we all know that but we
don't realize or don't think about why
that weakens the human system to
rejuvenate itself and therefore to
reverse chronic diseases or to teach the
body to
to make up for
that which is
not functioning anymore properly
we have known for a long time that the
brain can we
re-wire itself we call that right rewire
itself to adjust and make up for lost
faculties in one part and another part
will assume those abilities and the
brain gets rewired in quotation marks so
that we can make up for the deficiency
um one wonderful example of that is a
young blind man learned how to flick his
tongue and Echo locate the entire
landscape
so he does this clicking
like that and the echo that he perceives
allows him to literally see the
Landscapes the buildings arriving cars
so much so that he can bicycle
in the world so
it's pretty phenomenal
of course it it wouldn't work in a car
because you have to be exposed to the
sound waves that come back to you from
the environment
um so
the census can all be
not all you can't really say replace but
they can adjust to a lack of capability
and therefore
another capability
takes over and we can function very well
now I wanted to briefly talk about
what we call birth defects or weaknesses
that everybody is born with for the
longest time I've said you know disease
hits us where our body has
a weak spot
a um
a propensity a probably genetic weakness
that's why so many people insist not it
runs in the family so the genetic weak
spot may run in the family but it
doesn't mean that you wouldn't have the
capability of training your body to
better cope and better make up for that
weakness
um
now in today's statistics I just looked
and I thought oh my God
160 million Americans have one
or more chronic diseases as diagnosed
I mean that's just staggering
that would be the entire adult
population
or half of all humans more than half
of you know half of all humans living in
the US of a
have a diagnosed chronic disease that is
really phenomenal and staggering so the
definition of course having been
broadened to the phenomenon of obesity
Etc makes that more possible but it also
provides this incredible challenge that
we all should
face
and act upon
that we look at well
what can we do
how can we encourage our inherent
ability to
reinvent the body to rebuild the body
cell by cell tissue by tissue
so that chronic diseases disappear
um
now
some people will say well there's
nothing we can do because it's from
outside it's because the Chemtrails it's
because the chlorine in the water it's
because the electromagnetic fields in
the air it's because it's because it's
because and yes those are all factors
but this here body and the biology of
this body and this here mind
and the capability of this mind to
literally produce
um
to literally produce energy fields with
our thoughts and our emotions and our
intentions those are all areas in
which we have already traveled because
we know that
ultimately everything is energy
and that has been shown by Dr Joe
dispenza and many others the Dr geralt
future in in Germany and so many others
have shown the incredible power of the
mind to rewire itself and to rewire the
electromagnetic field around ourselves
with intention so there's so much more
to
our ability to self-heal
then meets the eye and certainly then
meets the diagnosis
um
a couple of examples
so
I was born with a little hole in my
heart I always had purple lips I still
to this day I always wear lipstick
because I don't want people to think oh
my God she's so sick
um but there's a weakness of course that
comes with a defective heart there's a
low blood pressure there's a disability
in sports you know you're just always
like oh I can't run so fast
like this and still
when we start working with this body
that we have lo and behold at age 64 I
ran my first half marathon
so there you have it no I'm not the
fastest and that's not the point the
point is that I am doing it and the
point is that I can train my body to
work with this heart in a way that is
very efficient and very much trained for
longevity and a happy functioning life
and that goes from many
genetic defects or birth defects
or
um propensities weaknesses that
each of us has
and in some of these
chronic diseases of course
we need to retrain our biology not just
to build new cell tissue
um as in for example diabetes we need to
retrain our body to produce the
appropriate amounts of insulin and the
appropriate amounts of
balance in that whole system of the
pancreatic excretions
and in our
um if we we look at
at asthma we need to retrain
the lung tissue to
appropriately
inhale exhale and we need to train the
body not to produce all this phlegm
which is actually
a reaction again to something we put
into our body are that falls upon our
body from the outside and or from the
inside
um
a reaction to toxins that the body tries
to excrete so when an asthmatic
person and yes I was raised together
with my younger Sisterhood very very
severe asthma and would like cough up
phlegm all night long and wheeze and
and my parents then sent her into a
boarding school in the Alps where the
air was easier to breathe and nobody
realized that it could have been
switched off in almost a heartbeat had
we discontinued our very heavy Dairy
consumption house milk creates in most
people phlegm production
so and of course there's plenty of of
proof and evidence for that in today's
scientific literature even but
culture is always stronger than reason
and therefore we do not take action in
that direction even if we know that
cheese and
and um
milk and butter and yogurt are all
um detrimental to human health
yeah people are falling in and out
hi Lori
so great to see you
and Michelle Michelle
great to see you
um so
when we are in a culture that has a
certain belief system
we are bound by that belief system
almost to our own
detriment of course definitely to our
own detriment but almost in
self-destruction
and I think there is another element to
this self-destruction
and that is that we have long as a
culture in many parts of the world
believe that suffering makes us somewhat
better human beings or or you know being
suffering through sickness
um matures us I know that that my
parents and and teachers who are talking
about you know every time you're sick
and you come through it you mature and
there's of course there's some truth to
it you know challenges mature us
but I think there's so many more
challenges in this world we shouldn't
just be busy challenging our own health
by destroying our own biology
and therefore I want to talk about what
we definitely can do
um
to reverse
chronic diseases and I'm throwing them
all into this one big bag you know why
because they are all reactions of our
body of our biology the same biology
because biology Works only in one way on
planet Earth
and I know that I always remind people
you know how does biology work it only
works one way on planet Earth I don't
know about planet Mars or other
universes out there but I know it only
works one way on planet Earth and that
is
by cell reproduction
and sell expansion
until we have everybody if we've lost
somebody people are coming in and out
um
and those cells that want to reproduce
and fix things and rebuild things
because all of life is a life cycle
right and new cell splits into two or in
a new cell emerges and it needs to be
informed of its task in the body
properly informed so that it can perform
that task in the body it needs to know I
need to be a liver cell I need to be a
blood cell I need to be a brain cell I
need to be a whatever other cell
um and if that information is not there
because the right nutrients are not
provided the right energies if you will
are not provided because of course
nutrients when you really really break
it down is also energy life energy is
not provided these cells don't know what
to do and they can become cancer cells
they can become
bacterial cells because a lot of
bacteria is needed to expel those toxins
and to try and fix up the inflammatory
situation in an arthritic knee for
example right
um so we're constantly trying to fix
ourselves
now the easy way in my book is to give
the biology of the body what it needs to
best do those tasks and it will start to
fix itself very rapidly
now what are those nutrients that we
most need
of course
um you know lately I explained to people
all of life feeds on other live
forms of life
alive things Every Breath You Take every
step you make I shall I'll be watching
you Every Breath You Take
inhale you has you inhale
trillions of bacteria
and tiny little living entities
right we kind of know that
but we don't want to kind of know that
because of what
because of germophobia
and it's such a schizophrenic mindset
that on the one hand we know that if we
have a sterile air and sterile water I
mean the air would be a vacuum if it
were totally sterile right
and we breathe and we live
and we function
not even for a few minutes
we die
all of life needs to constantly be
enlivened by other life forms all the
time
now let's distill that down to the human
consumption of life forms in in addition
to that live air that we need to inhale
what else do we need to we need to also
have Sunshine we need to have that UV
light even if the Sun is not shining
from the clouds the UV light so the
incredible vitamin D deficiency we call
that right stems mostly from a lack of
exposure to
UV light that is truly from the skies
and the Sunshine
so we need live air we need
Sunshine which is another form of energy
some say you know it's nuclear energy
the the good kind
excuse me and we need
of course water and
yeah today somebody
um I came across
was arguing that
um water and even salt of course we need
a little bit of salt it's in all plants
right
um
because it carries minerals into our
body and the water carries minerals into
our body if we denature the water we're
deprived of those minerals as well
the water that I drink here is from a
spring straight out of the mountains and
after several times filling up the glass
you will have sediments of like
powdered rock at the bottom because
that's the
mineral load that this water carries but
it's really delicious and really healthy
water
so even this water is alive
yeah and the argument was
um that
peltic sea salt is alive because it has
um fine life in it algae life
whereas Himalayan salt is dead because
it has been deep in the mountains for
millennia
um so this I'm sure there's some truth
to that as well now
what do we do with these chronic
diseases where do we start
any idea
does anybody want to communicate
we're opening The Forum now as to what
to do we've talked about the biology
we've talked about what creates healing
that cell reproduction
we talked about
the industry of The Chronic
situations
and of course disclaimer here I'm not a
medical professional and I don't intend
to be
giving medical advice
um
so and of course in addition to that
live
nutrient that we need to consume by the
way I have a really delicious live
nutrient here look at that
it's chocolate mousse with strawberries
and it's all alive would you believe in
um
there's also of course
the fact that our biology needs physical
movement
like all life forms need some kind of
movements
um
of course even a tree though it stands
still moves inside of it all the time
right it grows and then of course it
sheds the leaves and it grows new ones
and it has this flow of of liquid going
up the tree trunk under just under the
bark and into all the little branches
um so
all life forms while alive also need
movement and some need more and some
need less now we humans being mammals
need a lot of movement think of all the
other mammals which of them lays around
well the bears go to sleep I guess the
um the bears go to sleep for for a few
months every winter right
so they just breathe very shallowly
throughout those months that they're
asleep and then they have to eat a lot
um but all mammals also require
hi Monique require movement so exercise
we call that today is necessary because
we don't have
the need anymore to go out and dig for
food or pick the apples or go even as a
child I still needed to go shopping down
the street and carry heavy bags home and
with the potatoes and the flour and
whatever we were buying
but
we've eliminated all of that because the
Amazon
person comes and drops the parcel in
front of the door and all we need to do
is open it and once or something
um so yeah we need movement and we need
live ingestion how do we best do that
we do that by cleansing the body first
with I don't believe in water fast but I
do think that
um
smoothie cleanses I'm sure water fasts
have lots of benefits but in my
particular condition with that little
hole and the low blood pressure and all
of that water fast and not the best
answer
but
hyper nutrition is and there are many
um
alternative
people now alternative natural
um
healers and nutritional Doctors Now who
will use what is called hypernutrition
meaning that we
densely consume fresh raw of course
always organic no exceptions always
organic greens and fruits because they
contain the highest density of nutrients
that help us get all the vitamin C's and
A's and E's and then we have to add the
bees that vitamin B's that is not the
bees that visit and find the honey
the vitamin B's
that come in the grains and nuts and
um
and
yeah B12 is a whole other story I can
talk about that it's very important and
we don't have it because we
we clean our stuff instead of eating it
straight out of the earth and getting a
little dirt on there because of course
B12 is a microbe that we need and need
to consume it from dirt or from
yeah people cringe forgive me but it's
actually an excrement so when they're
when they're worms and beetles and tiny
little decomposers go through our good
dirt in which good vegetables can grow
then
their their trans they are transforming
the dirt into the fertile
um the fertile dirt that becomes the
fertilizer for a good
plant life
and um
so that's where the the B12 is to be
found that's where the cows get their
B12 and and or the the elephants and or
the you know all these big animals the
giraffes Etc because they will consume
some of that
um
some of that dirt or also
um think of
an elephant consuming the whole branches
of trees
um where the
tiny little critters and creatures on
the leaves are providing the B12
as opposed to Earth or soil
okay no
I have personally seen people reverse
their chronic diseases in record time
but then of course you need to carry it
through
to create a lifestyle that allows you to
not fall back because once the body has
been weakened by a chronic disease it is
so much easier to fall back and I like
to tell a story of somebody who is dying
from liver
um cirrhosis liver decomposition it's
the end of life stage
um when the liver cannot handle what
you're putting into your body most of
the time it's alcohol and drugs or
um or the liver is already very weak
um
maybe from a jaundice
situation something like that so then
this there's the story of this young man
having liver failure and being on his
deathbed and
um these the the Victoria butenko family
find him and
he agrees to allow them to give him
again green smoothies and just very
carefully raw food only only only raw
food
for a whole
months and then three months and he
recovers beautifully and he starts
building
they were building some kind of a
block house a wooden house at the time
so he's building with them and he's
getting strong and Fabulous
and then he meets a girl and wants to
take her out to dinner
and wants to be the man and that's his
background and that's his
um vision of
the masculine man and he ordered his
ribs
eats those ribs
and dies the next day
so that is to say that you can bring
your body back
but it will be frail for a whole while
until you've really established a
lifestyle that can support and
strengthen your system
now
when you look at me as an example I've
had my stroke at 50 and this year going
to be 70
so it's almost 20 years now
um
and in that stroke situation
being completely paralyzed but conscious
I decided I'm going to have the
healthiest lifestyle ever
and that was going to
raw organic raw plant-based food
and the proof is in the pudding and of
course you know many of my clients have
gone through similar
um
Journeys and we can all have this
experience of self-healing
now I do want to hear from you
from Michelle and Monique and
and Leah I I know Leah's situation
[Music]
um
and I know Shirley has been working at
keeping herself strong
and yeah
just this morning I was sitting
with a dear friend and and contractor
who's working with me
um
and he was explaining to me that he
spends he spent thousands of dollars you
know trying to demonstrate and show
people and convince people that they
should do the right thing and get
healthy as opposed to taking certain
poisons Etc that would further impair
them
and I said we cannot convince others
against their will when they are not
ready so if you're ready
tell me now
and let's work on your particular
situation and let's get you to the
exercise program you need and the food
program you need to create longevity and
happiness because the other thing is you
know like I was discussing this morning
with this friend
um it's interesting once you are on that
smoothie cleanse for example after day
three everybody says the brain fog
cleared
I can't believe how clear my mind is
what is this this is crazy so that's
what everybody is experiencing so
sometimes when people say well I'm too
depressed to get started
we have to do it the other way around we
have to get started to get out of the
depression to be able to want to live a
happy long life again right
so I'm
I'm always
um wavering between asking somebody who
wants to be my client well do you really
want to live because that's important
and there was well of course you know
who doesn't why would I not want to live
and then I say well why
and there has to be some kind of reason
and sometimes they say I don't know
and
we have to dig for that reason what is
your mission what do you want to share
with Humanity what do you want to give
or what do you want to experience still
some people will just say well I want to
see some of the world still because I
haven't
and that's good enough reason you need a
functioning body to go see the world
obviously right
so we work on exactly what it is that
helps you to get your body in the shape
to achieve that Vision that you had once
often it is you know well when I was a
child I loved lying under trees and
looking out into the trees and hearing
the insects Buzz Etc okay so what is it
you want to do
well maybe a summer camp but then I
don't really want to work with kids okay
so we got to a glamping business and he
is now
has started his glamping business so
this is just you know one example of how
you slowly get there and he says yeah it
became clear because my mind suddenly
was able to focus and suddenly was able
to make decisions
it's incredible how
decision making is not something that
comes easy
but anybody
okay who is saying I just wanted to
participate Michelle
was that you texting
yes can you hear me yes I can hear you
loud and clear welcome it's great to see
you great to see you too I was just on
email and I saw that you had your
webinar starting so I just thought I
would listen and participate while I
could wonderful
um I I know I text you often to get your
goodies to get your hit veggie burgers
and I'm trying to
you know do I went to Hippocrates so I
try to follow
a monthly raw I do though in the winter
you know probably 60 to 75 raw and now
as we move into spring
um and I have an early I had an early
stage of breast cancer but everything is
okay right now and so just trying to
maintain a healthy lifestyle and
yeah Michelle can I ask you quickly did
you have that that brain fog experience
brain ah like lifting no I felt
much better but it took a good week I
felt you know it took a good week for my
body to like transition
uh and feel better by the second week I
was feeling better but the first week I
was still feeling a little bit
um
yeah yeah just like things needed to
shift but after yeah yeah it's it's
amazing and and of course it also
depends a little bit on how extreme that
that transition is I mean in at
Hippocrates you still get a full meal
right in the in the evening yes so it
takes a little bit longer and of course
people have experienced the healing even
when going just organic Whole Food
cooked food or or half and half kind of
thing it still works but instead of
three weeks it takes three months and so
that's I often say if you really want
fast results then the smoothie cleanse
or juice cleanse which I'm not so fond
of because it it often lacks the fiber
to wash out your colon which is always
full of if you've had a anywhere
close to a regular diet you know
so yeah and and yeah I know they're fans
of just the regular juicing not the
smoothies but
um yeah I know I've I had this all right
this this discussion with Brian many
many times so yeah but I I have to go
but thank you so much and I'll try to
make the next one
very good I'll be in touch via text
about ordering some more goodies okay
yeah actually I just got an order today
so I'll be in the in the kitchen making
because I yeah I still don't have a
factory as you may know yes so yeah
thank you so much
thanks for for joining
have a great Sunday everybody
yeah thank you
all right let's give Michelle some love
and how does this work actually I never
do this
oh no I only get the heart she doesn't
get that hard
okay
um
all right Monique do you want to share
um you have to unmute yourself if you
are available
and Shirley is is doing the right thing
already
which is good
so
and Leah needs to get started
and we'll talk about getting you started
anyway I'm I'm offering
from I'm offering exercises twice a week
um currently I have it at 1pm because my
Irish
um
former assistant in Zimbabwe wants to
join
the world is such a small place now
she's now in Ireland
um
so Mondays and Wednesdays
at 1 pm I will be doing my exercise
program and you can join that for 25 a
month and after that at 2PM I will be
talking generally about certain topics
of health and can address particular
problems just verbally
um
and of course
if you are listening to this Mastermind
at a different time and have a chronic
disease that needs attention and you
really want to establish the lifestyle
to get you out of all your chronic
diseases
then you will want to join the super
happy body class which is a 12-month
course I'm now doing it you can join
anytime
and it but it follows a quite a strict
program to
um go through different experiences from
the always starting in my life always
starting with the smoothie cleanse or
the Smoothie Feast it's really more like
the Smoothie Feast so it's lots of
high density nutrients and of course
um to to
round out Michelle's
mention of you know that I have these
arguments with Dr Brian Clement over
juice versus smoothie
um that my my other colleague Dr
uh Brooke goldner who
famously wrote goodbye lupus does the
high density smoothie
cleanse so or or Feast if you will so
high cruciferous green smoothie cleanse
and has phenomenal results with that so
the proof again is in the pudding they
all work and they all work slightly
differently but they do all work all
these approaches I just like smoothies
better and I make a sweet one and a
Savory one which is the other thing that
I like you know that that in the
Smoothie operation you can have a like a
salad smoothie but that's a little spicy
and with with garlic and stuff in it and
all lots of greens and cucumbers and
avocados and then you can have the sweet
smoothie sweet and quotation marks with
also cruciferous greens like cabbage and
and kale but then on top banana and
mango and berries so that you can have
a
a very fruity sweet experience versus
the
um Savory experience and can have both
and you feel very satiated and satisfied
so we'll be having our next smoothie
cleanse soon and that's something you
can sign up for that's a little bit more
it's ninety seven dollars for the
smoothie cleanse it's a seven day
smoothie cleanse
um where we meet every day and get
recipes and talk about results Etc
and
um
yeah and then of course the the big
program continues with trauma work
because we all also have emotional
mental trauma
one way or another
and that we need to come to terms with
that but I don't just want you to come
to terms with what you've experienced I
want you to use what you've experience
and I should call it turn your traumas
into tools and actually Brian said to me
Johanna can I steal that and I said yes
of course
turn your traumas into tools so that's
another thing where I work with people
individually to see where their traumas
is and how that can Empower them for the
next chapter of their life and then
there's exercise programs and breathing
programs and then there's the whole you
know what's in your household
products education on what you should
and should not have in your household
and
um how you deal with your
um from your laundry to your shampoo
right everything
and
and then you create a lifestyle and of
course purpose is very important what's
your purpose what do you want to do next
what do you want to accomplish where do
you want to earn your money if that is a
goal
and how can that be done using online
modalities using even
yes even chat GPT can be it can be
included it's a new thing
um where we can communicate quickly with
people and with a lot of people to find
who needs what we have to offer because
you know as my business coach used to
say and still says you know in today's
world we're not selling a product we're
allowing people to benefit from our
particular way of doing things and
allowing people to create their own way
of doing things by giving them a
structure of how they can get there and
not to be
carbon copies of me but to create in you
that which is your best health and your
best
happiness that's why my program is
called the super happy body because you
need a super happy body to do what you
really want to do in life most
effectively
so
that's it for today's masterminds now
I've asked you guys to ask questions
Leah can can you unmute yourself on the
phone and and ask a question if anything
comes up Monique can you ask a question
surely can you ask a question
oh
yes of course you know teeth
um
Monique teeth are of course part of our
bone structure and very much genetically
inherited weakness mine are a very good
example I just broke one of my my um
my self-fabricated fake teeth that I
literally make myself so you can
certainly learn that from me how to do
that if you know you don't want to wear
the regular you know get everything
pulled and want to get the regular
dentures
which I still don't want to do years ago
actually 30 years ago dentists have
already said to me you know just get
everything pulled and get either
implants or dentures because you know
your teeth material is so
or that it's just not going to last but
look here these are all real still these
are all still mine and
they're fully functional and then I make
my own there's there's a way of making
your own it's not very complicated
um if you still have
uh teeth on both sides of where the
teeth are missing so that you can
pluck like build your own bridge and
pluck it in between
um and there's a biodegradable material
that I use
that is non-toxic probably less toxic
actually than wearing those Dentures
Dentures but I you know I haven't
researched it it's just the easier
way of going about it and then um
then yeah having everything removed and
implants can cause all kinds of other
issues so Monique if you want to learn
that
um please
allow me to connect with you so I will I
will do that so
I will connect with you to see if we can
help you with the tooth issue or find
ways to
allow you to find a place that is
Affordable which is the other issue you
know do I really want to throw twenty
thousand dollars at my teeth because
even in a cheap version of denture
um of implants that's that's what they
would cost
um
so do I do I really want to throw money
at that or do I want to do something
more meaningful with those kind of
dollars if I have them
so
I'll connect with you on
on teeth and
surviving deteriorating teeth of course
a lot of the fat I mean the fact that I
even still have what I still have has to
do with me changing my diet and my
lifestyle altogether as well
but
yeah we got to deal with what we we
can't regrow teeth that's definitely one
thing that we cannot do
only young children can actually regrow
enamel over small cavities with
um
the right High nutrient dense foods but
at our age we cannot
all right
good
um
Charlie any question you might want to
ask
well
I'll tell you I can you hear me yes
and you can imagine I had perfect
beautiful teeth
that is amazing and now not now well
what I did was when I went to
rejuvenate my sister's place to add
these
lemon trees
Mario lemon tree and I started eating
the lemons oh
and my sweet
well it didn't happen right away like
cheese started so you think that the
lemons affected your teeth
yes
interesting because then the dentist
said and grapefruit
yeah well
honestly surely I tend to not believe
that but
um well the dentist then did say that
the uh
the lemons and the grapefruit like that
remove the enamel
break down the enamel yeah but you have
to have already very weak enamel for
that to even happen because of course
many cultures that are known for good
teeth eat those fruits all day long
because they grow in those regions right
um like Mediterranean
Etc I understand I also started using
baking soda
yeah and baking soda I no longer use but
I use it for a number of years that was
a wrong thing to use I thought okay
that's something natural
yeah
you're not fluoride
yeah but on the other hand you know
citrus fruits are actually alkalizing
they are not acidifying in the body
they're alkalizing
the whole pH level in your body so
that's an established fact so I just
want to make sure that we don't construe
this as you know citrus fruits are
suddenly bad for your teeth they are not
um but of course dentists don't know
anything about they just think okay sour
acid you know eats up the enamel well
the the fluoride in your toothpaste can
do that but not the
lemon I I just I just want to put that
out there
well through the National Health
ventilation I used to Lobby against uh
yeah and yeah there are of course other
um
toothpaste
um that
I mean for I've I've not used toothpaste
for many many years now I use a little
bit because I like the high Menthol and
effect and the um
and the the charcoal
whitening effect
um I use a charcoal men charcoal
peppermint paste that is sort of very
very basic of course no fluoride or any
of those things Alice and then I did not
have my teeth cleaned for four years
yeah you know
yeah I just want to caution people
against thinking that the dentists know
what kind of foods are good for you
cheese for the most part they have no
idea because that's not what they study
and of course you know it is their
business to do cleansing and cleaning
and I mean I yeah I'm going to go and
have the remaining teeth cleaned
and then I went to a holistic dentist I
was darling about yeah seven years ago
so they know a little bit more that's
good but he uses ozone ozone uh coconut
ozone
ozone therapy can be very effective
you're not I
ozon is a wonderful thing because the
higher you climb in the high mountains
on this planet like I've been on
three and a half thousand meters that's
like
seeing that's like yeah 11 12
000 feet
um Peaks
you know where there's no tree growth
just rocks and
and up there the air is so thin that it
smells much more like ozone
it's it's really cool but yeah that's
what the Himalayas which I got stranded
over the Himalayas in Nepal 55 years ago
you were there yes
yes
I saved my money because I knew uh and I
was uh I was a teacher and I knew I met
these teachers on these trips and none
of them could get out of the boat and
walk they had eaten like when I was two
TV behind the favorite thing to eat I
can't hear you anymore shortly but um
but you were in the Himalayas 55 years
ago that is the coolest thing and I
think on that note we shall close
because we're over our time and it's
been wonderful having you that I think
that's so awesome that you know we we
allow ourselves to have those
experiences on this little planet
that I just
mind-boggling and super important that
we have them so and yeah and and we get
in we get a little bit of a taste of
what ozone tastes like when the air gets
thinner up there right
yes now everyone no one else from our
group from a group of students with USF
University so poor credit wanted to go
out they wanted to have hamburgers
wherever they want McDonald's
but most of them are probably no longer
on this planet but you are
a lot just in the past four years taking
care of my husband who passed away I
know practicing I know surely but I'm
going to close right now on this note
that you went to the Himalayas I want
everybody to find their Himalayas to go
to and go there with a functioning body
and take example because Shirley is in
her 80s and she's fit and she's capable
and I love it and I want us all to learn
from each other how to maintain and re
reinvigorate ourselves and get rid of
those chronic diseases because yes we
can
and I'm going to talk to you guys soon
hasta luego until next time
see
bye everybody thank you Joanna hi Leah
I'm gonna be in touch
Superwoman Joanna
thank you
super smoothing
all right
thank you